Guide to the Walter Lippmann "Today and Tomorrow" Columns,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Walter Lippmann "Today and Tomorrow" Columns,
1931-1950.
Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.
ca. 1,200 items (6 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079034
Biographical Note
Journalist, author.
Scope and Content
Photostatic copies of Lippmann's syndicated column, Today and Tomorrow, 1931-1949, and two books written by Lippmann: The Cold War, New York, Harper & Bros., 1947; and A Preface To Morals, New York, Macmillan, 1929. Also, eleven scrapbooks of clippings, 1931-1933, 1936, 1938-1944, and 1947-1950.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 3 series:
Series I: Today and Tomorrow
Series II: Scrapbooks
Series III: Books
Subjects
Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.; Scrapbooks.; Journalists.; American authors.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1951 M-51 Purchase
- Series I: Today and Tomorrow
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, September-December 1931 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-April 1932 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, May-August 1932 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, September-December 1932 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1933 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1933 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1933 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1933 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1934 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1934 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1934 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1935 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1935 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1935 (Box 1)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, Januaty-March 1936 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1936 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1937 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1937 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1937 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1938 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-August 1938 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, September-December 1938 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1939 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-September 1939 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1939 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1940 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1940 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1940 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1940 (Box 2)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1941 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1941 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1941 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1941 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1942 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1942 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1942 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1942 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1943 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1943 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1943 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1943 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1944 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1944 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1944 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1944 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1945 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1945 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1945 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1945 (Box 3)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1946 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1946 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-September 1946 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, October-December 1946 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1947 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1947 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1947 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1948 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, April-June 1948 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, July-December 1948 (Box 4)
  - Photostats of the column, New York Herald Tribune, January-March 1949 (Box 4)
- Series II: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, 1931/1932 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1941 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1949 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1949/1950 (Box 6)
- Series III: Books
  - Lippmann, Walter A Preface to Morals, New York: Macmillan, 1929 (Box 5)
    [Inscribed: "To Dad from Bryce / Christmas 1929"]
  - Lippmann, Walter The Cold War, New York: Harper & Bros., 1947 (Box 5)
    [Inscribed: "For Your 'academic' shelf / Love Chveky"]